現状　情報が少ないからね。
Currently, we lack information.
心がないパターンも
考えた方がいい。
We should consider the possibility
that it doesn't have a mind.
その場合は
力業になるだろうけどね。
In which case, we'll probably
have to use brute force.
できるのか？
Can you do it?
さぁ　分かんない。
I don't know.
In that case,
あの　それでしたら
もしかしたら私　フリーレン様を
殺せるかもしれません。
I may be able to kill Ms. Frieren.
ん…⁉
そう。
はい…。
Oh?
Yes.
じゃあ　作戦を立てようか。
Well, then...
Let's come up with a strategy.
You're there like the wind
Closing your eyes at sunset
I wonder what's on your mind
Beyond Journey's End
With your eyelids open
Your eyes shone like glass
It faintly smelled like a sunny day
Clear up the sky, let flowers bloom
Bloom and blame it on the sunny sky
Even the rain, when it stops
Will make you shine in the sunlight
Calm the stirring sounds in my heart
We go like the sunny wind
Go on and fly over that cloud
Further and further away
Episode 25: A Fatal Vulnerability
To confirm: if the replica has a mind,
じゃあ　まず確認だけど
複製体に心がある場合は
エーデルの精神魔法を使って
私の精神防御を破って
we'll use Edel's hypnosis magic
to penetrate my mental defenses,
フェルンが殺すってことで
いいね？
and Fern will kill me.
はい。
いや　「はい」って…。
Yes.
"Yes"?
う…。
Mr. Dünste.
ドゥンストさん。
う…。
Where is Ms. Edel?
エーデルさんは？
ゼンゼさんの複製体に襲われて
She dropped out when we were
attacked by Sense's replica.
脱落しました。
そうですか…　ブライさんも？
I see. Mr. Blei as well?
彼の足止めのおかげで
逃げ切ることができたのです。
I was able to escape because he kept it busy.
無事に脱出できていると
いいのですが…。
I hope he made it out safely.
ぐわ！
あっ！
構うな　行け！
Leave me! Go!
う…
し…　しかし…
B-But...
It's better than neither of us passing.
合格者なしよりマシだ
情報があります　協力しませんか？
I have information.
Why don't we work together?
儂は初めから　そのつもりだった。
That was my intention from the start.
治療ができる者はいるか？
Is there anyone who can treat this man?
I have a holy scripture.
I can cast simple healing spells.
聖典を持っていますので
簡単な回復魔法くらいなら。
頼む。
Please.
なるほど。
I see.
The replicas don't have minds.
複製体に心はないんだね。
はい　エーデルさんの見立てでは
No. According to Ms. Edel,
心の働きを精密に
模倣しているだけで
they merely imitate the
functions of a mind precisely
心そのものは　ないそうです。
without actually having one.
これで
楽に倒せる手段はなくなったね。
Well, there goes the easy way
of taking one down.
それを踏まえた上で
作戦を立てないと。
We'll have to plan accordingly.
But, Frieren, there's still
too much that we don't know.
とはいっても　フリーレン。
まだ不確定要素が多過ぎる。
The biggest question is: what are those
replicas, and who created them?
一番の問題は　あの複製体と
その術者の正体だ。
その性質が分からんまま
手は出せん。
We can hardly take them on
without knowing their nature.
特に複製体特有の弱点は
本当にないのかだ。
In particular, we need to know whether
or not the replicas themselves
have any unique weaknesses.
仮に　あの複製体が
フリーレンと同じ実力なら
If that replica really is as strong as you,
then we'd likely suffer casualties.
死傷者が出かねない。
私は答えんぞ。
I won't answer that question.
Didn't think you would.
だろうな。
They don't have any weaknesses.
複製体に弱点はないぜ。
複製体を操っているのは
The replicas are being controlled
水鏡の悪魔っていう
神話の時代の魔物だ。
by a monster from the mythical era
known as the Spiegel.
ラヴィーネ。
なぜ知っている？
Lawine.
How do you know that?
一番上の兄貴が大陸魔法協会の
My oldest brother was in the advance party
that the Continental Magic Association
零落の王墓攻略の
先遣隊の一人だったんだ。
sent into the Tomb of the Ruined King.
So you had information.
No wonder you made it this far.
情報を持っていたわけか。
道理で　ここまで来れたわけだ。
But you made an irrational choice.
だが　とても合理的とは思えんな。
それならば　初めから
俺たちと情報を共有して
You should've shared your information
and worked with us from the start.
協力するべきだった。
協力できるような
雰囲気じゃなかったからな。
It didn't feel like we could've at the time.
フリーレンたちは　気が付いたら
先に行っちゃっていたしね。
And Frieren and Fern left before we knew it.
それに　おっさんは
ルールがなければ
Besides, old man,
you're the type to mercilessly abandon
your allies unless there are rules against it.
容赦なく
仲間を見捨てるタイプだろ。
フ…。
安易に協力できるか。
Anyone would think twice
about working with you.
ふん。
嫌われたものだな。
She really doesn't like you.
確かに俺は　おっさんだが
It's true that I'm old,
面と向かって言われると
くるものがあるな。
but there's something that stings
about having it said to my face.
Maybe you should apologize.
謝った方がいいんじゃない？
悪かったな　おっさん。
Sorry, old man.
フ…。
先遣隊の観測結果によると
According to the advance party's
observation report,
水鏡の悪魔は　あの扉の向こう側
宝物庫の内部にいて
the Spiegel is in the treasure room
on the other side of that door.
本体は攻撃手段を持たない
脆弱な魔物だって話だ。
The monster itself is weak
and has no way of attacking directly.
そいつを倒せば
複製体は全部消える。
Once we defeat it,
all the replicas will disappear.
That matches what our mana detection revealed.
こちらの魔力探知の結果と
一致するな。
本体は扉の向こう側だ。
The monster is on the other side of the door,
but it's shut fast with a
powerful sealing spell.
だが　あの扉には
強力な封印が施されている。
それは私も確認している。
I've confirmed that as well.
My replica must've done it.
私の複製体の仕業だね。
「命懸けで
宝物庫の扉を閉じる魔法」。
It's a spell that shuts the door of a
treasure vault at the risk of your life.
民間魔法の中でも
トップクラスの封印魔法だよ。
Even among folk magic,
it's a top-class sealing spell.
あの扉は術者が死ぬまで
開くことはない。
That door won't open
until the caster is dead.
扉を避けて壁を破るという
方法もあるけど
We could ignore the door
and break through a wall,
多分　それも対処済みだろうね。
but they've probably already
accounted for that.
どちらにせよ
水鏡の悪魔をたたくには
Either way, we'll have to defeat that replica
if we want to take down the Spiegel.
あの複製体は
倒さねばならんということか。
倒すなら急いだ方がいいぜ。
If we want to take it down,
then we'd better hurry.
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
水鏡の悪魔は
The Spiegel creates replicas
of everyone within the dungeon.
迷宮の中にいるヤツ全員の
複製体を作り出す。
その複製体は時間とともに
Over time, the replicas begin to gather
at the bottom of the dungeon.
最深部に集まってくる
っていう習性がある。
前回の先遣隊は
Aside from my brother's unit, most members
of the advance party died...
兄貴の部隊を除いて
ほとんどが壊滅した。
最深部目前の
ちょうど　この場所でだ。
right here, just before the bottom.
あ…。
I see.
なるほどな。
あの…。
Excuse me.
複製体は心の働きを
精密に模倣しているんですよね。
The replicas precisely imitate the
functions of a mind, don't they?
なら　行動パターンによる弱点は
本人と同じなんですよね。
In that case, any vulnerabilities
in their behavioral patterns
would be the same as the original's, right?
恐らくは。
Probably.
それなら　やっぱり
何とかなるかもしれません。
In that case, we may have a chance.
その弱点って何なの？
What vulnerability are you thinking of?
フリーレン様　あっちの壁際に
立ってもらってもいいですか？
Ms. Frieren, could you go stand by that wall?
うん。
Okay.
これは…。
まさか…。
Was that…?
Incredible. I don't believe it.
何ということだ…。
Did you notice?
気が付きましたか。
何か分かった？
分からん。
Did you?
Nope.
確かに　これは
フリーレンの致命的な隙だ。
This is Frieren's fatal vulnerability.
なぜ戦っている時に
気が付かなかったんだ。
Why didn't I notice when I fought her?
いや　手だれという
先入観があったからこそ
No, I couldn't notice because of my
preconceptions about experienced mages.
気付けなかった。
ん？
魔法を使う瞬間に　ほんの一瞬だけ
魔力探知が途切れている。
When casting a spell, she stops
detecting mana for a brief moment.
それって
見習い魔法使いが
Isn't that a common mistake
made by apprentice mages?
よくするミスじゃ…。
昔から苦手なんだよね。
I've never been very good about it.
自覚があるのなら　何で
言ってくれなかったんですか？
If you're aware of it,
then why didn't you say anything?
だって　恥ずかしいし…。
Because it's embarrassing.
そんなことを
言っている場合ですか。
This is hardly the time to be saying that.
しかし　他の技量が
あまりにも卓越し過ぎている。
But she's far too skilled in all other areas.
実際に
この隙を突ける魔法使いなど
I can't imagine there are many mages
who could exploit that vulnerability.
ほとんどいないだろう。
In any case, let's discuss our strategy.
とにかく　作戦会議をしますよ。
フリーレンの複製体は
何とかなるとして…。
Supposing we can handle Frieren's replica,
what about the others?
フリーレン様
何だか楽しそうですね。
Won't they all disappear
if we defeat the Spiegel?
Ms. Frieren, you seem to be having fun.
The replicas will probably
gather before then.
Yeah.
うん。
大きな足音
うなり声
大体まとまったな
Sounds like we've got a plan.
Eisen will draw the enemy to him,
and I'll attack from the flank.
それじゃあ
アイゼンが敵を引き付けて
側面から攻撃しよう
ん
フリーレンは援護射撃だ
Frieren, you'll provide supporting fire.
ハイターは？
What about Heiter?
Today's an off day for him. He's hungover.
今日は二日酔いでダメな日だ
死んでる…
He's dead.
ドラゴンのうなり声
咆哮
ドラゴンが倒れた音
こうやって
迷宮のボスを倒すために
I was just thinking about
all the times we discussed
よく話し合ったなって思って。
how we'd beat the dungeon boss like this.
よし　攻略を開始しようか。
Okay.
Let's begin the attack.
勝てるのか？
Can we win?
大丈夫。
Don't worry. There isn't a dungeon
that can't be conquered.
攻略できない迷宮なんか
存在しない。
私は歴史上で
I'm the mage of the party that cleared
the most dungeons in history.
最も多くの迷宮を攻略した
パーティーの魔法使いだよ。
Are you two sure you don't need any help
fighting Frieren's replica?
本当に
フリーレンの複製体と戦うのは
お前たち２人だけで
大丈夫なのか？
The fewer of us there are, the easier
it will be to predict its movements.
少人数の方が相手の行動を
予測しやすいからね。
確かに全員で戦えば
ほぼ確実に勝てるだろうけど
We'd almost certainly win if we all fought,
but most of us would probably die.
大半が死ぬことになると思う。
多分　脱出用ゴーレムを
使うような暇もないよ。
I doubt we'd even have the time
to use our escape golems.
それよりも
最深部に集まってくる複製体の
So slowing down the replicas gathering
at the bottom is more important.
足止めの方が重要というわけか。
挟み撃ちにされたら
私たちは全滅だからね。
If they surround us, we're all dead.
じゃあ　作戦通りに。
Follow the plan.
Got it. Good luck.
ああ　健闘を祈る。
それじゃ　開けて。
Open the door.
さて…。
Now, then.
このメンバーの中で
苦手な相手を言い合おうか。
Let's discuss our weakest matchups.
破滅の雷を放つ魔法。
Judradjim.
フリーレン様の
予想した行動パターン通りだ
It's behaving just like Ms. Frieren predicted.
地獄の業火を出す魔法。
Vollzanbel.
魔力探知が途切れた
I stopped detecting mana.
その隙に潜伏したフェルンを
複製体は警戒する
I'll be wary of Fern,
who used that opportunity to hide.
でも　目の前の
互角の相手の対処で手いっぱい
But I'll be busy dealing with
the equally-matched opponent in front of me.
フェルンを探す余裕なんて
あるはずがない
I won't have time to look for Fern.
だって
After all, no one knows better than I do
how frightening I can be.
私の怖さは
私が一番よく分かっている
大丈夫だよ
You'll be all right.
Not even I can easily detect you
when you're completely hidden.
完壁に潜伏したフェルンは
私でも　そう簡単に探知できない
でも　本当に攻撃に使う魔法は
Are you sure I should use
Zoltraak to attack, though?
一般攻撃魔法でいいのですか？
最も速射性に
優れているからね
It's the quickest spell there is.
それに　一般攻撃魔法は
Besides, Zoltraak is a relatively
new spell for elves.
エルフにとっては
比較的　新しい魔法だから
反射神経で無意識に
防御できるほどの年月は
Not enough time has passed for us
to reflexively defend against it.
たっていないんだ
どうしても
その対処は　たった一瞬
It takes only a moment
for us to respond to it,
ほんの誤差のような
時間だけれども
思考する分だけ
遅れることになる
but the time we spend thinking
about it causes a delay.
でも　フェルンは違う
You're different, though.
フェルンにとって
一般攻撃魔法は
Zoltraak has existed since your birth.
To you, it's nothing special.
生まれた時からあって
当たり前のもので
It's a fundamental mage spell
engraved into your being.
その身に刻まれていて当然の
魔法使いの基礎だ
フェルンの一般攻撃魔法なら
私を殺せる
Your Zoltraak can kill me.
ありったけの魔力を
たたき込むんだ
Hit it with all the mana you've got.
フリーレン
Frieren, I thought you didn't like me.
お前は私のことが嫌いだろう
Why have you come to see me?
なぜ　私の元に来た？
Honestly, I thought we'd never meet again.
正直　もう二度と
会わないものだと思っていた
師匠の遺言状を届けに来た
I came to deliver my master's will.
あれから５０年
It's been fifty years.
そうか　フランメは死んだのか
I see. So Flamme has died.
悲しくないの？
You're not sad?
気まぐれで育てた弟子だ
I only trained her on a whim.
It's practically a report.
まるで報告書だな
何が書いてあったの？
What does it say?
皇帝が　国を挙げた魔法の研究に
認可を下ろしたそうだ
The emperor has authorized
magical research nationwide.
人間の文化圏では
Until now, human societies have considered
magic to be a technique used by demons,
今まで　魔法は
魔族の技術であるとして
表立った研究は
禁忌とされてきた
and openly studying it was forbidden.
働きかけたのはフランメで
Flamme encouraged him to allow it
彼女は　新設された
宮廷魔法使いとやらの
and had been training the newly
established imperial mages.
教育に携わっていた
私にそれを引き継いでほしい
という内容だ
She wants me to take over for her.
Such greed.
何て　贅沢なヤツだ
Receiving authorization to study magic
is a feat on its own, but she wants more.
魔法の研究の認可が
下りただけでも
快挙だというのに
それ以上を望むとは
それって　すごいことなの？
Is that such an impressive achievement?
大陸最大の統一帝国が
The continent's largest united empire
is set to begin studying magic
魔法の研究と軍事転用を
始めるということだ
and adopting it for military use.
周辺諸国が黙っていない
The neighboring nations are sure to respond.
わずか数十年で
魔法は大陸中に普及する
In just a few decades, magic will
spread throughout the continent.
人類の誰もが魔法を使える
時代がやってくるんだ
We'll enter an era in which
all of humanity can use magic.
これは遠くない未来に
In the near future,
人類が　魔王軍にあらがう力を
手に入れることを意味する
humanity will acquire the strength to fight
back against the Demon King's forces.
そう　すごいことだね　とても
I see. That's incredible.
まったくだ
Indeed it is.
だが　それは
私の望むところではない
But that's not what I want.
Leave, Frieren.
帰れ　フリーレン
こんな遺言は
到底　聞き入れられん
I can't comply with this final request.
実に不愉快だ
I find it truly displeasing.
誰もが
魔法を使える時代だと？
An era in which anyone can use magic?
魔法は特別であるべきだ
Magic should be special.
I won't teach anyone who lacks talent.
才ある者以外に
教えるつもりはない
こんなものをよこすとは
How dare she send this to me?
フランメとは
最後まで分かり合えなかった
Flamme and I remained unable to understand
each other until the very end.
しょせんは
気まぐれで育てた弟子だ
She was only ever a student
I trained on a whim.
師匠は
My master said you'd probably
get upset and tear up her will.
「ゼーリエは怒って
遺言状を破り捨てるだろう」
…って言っていたよ
But she wanted to tell you her dream
had come true regardless.
それでも
伝えておきたかったんだって
夢がかなったよって
よく分からないよね
It doesn't make sense, does it?
じゃあ　私は行くね
Well, I'm leaving now.
多分　もう
会うこともないと思う
I doubt we'll meet again.
フリーレン
Frieren.
その前に少し歩かないか
Before you go, walk with me a little.
どうせ私たちには
時間は　いくらでもあるんだ
After all, we have all the time in the world.
誰もが魔法を使える時代は
An era in which anyone could use magic
was Flamme's dream.
フランメの夢だった
あの子も　きっと初めは
I doubt she cared about helping humanity
人類のためとか
魔王軍にあらがう力とか
or the strength to fight the
Demon King's forces at first.
そんなものは
どうでもよかったんだ
あの子のお気に入りの魔法を
知っているか？
Do you know what her favorite spell was?
「花畑を出す魔法」
A spell to create a field of flowers.
何の役にも立たない
くだらない魔法だ
A useless, foolish spell.
あの子は本当に
魔法が好きだったんだ
She truly loved magic.
世界中の人が　そんな魔法を
使えるようになってほしいと
She genuinely wished for everyone in the
world to be able to cast spells like that.
本気で願っていた
むしずが走ったよ
It disgusted me.
まるで女の子みたいな
かわいい夢だ
It was the fanciful dream of a girl,
but it's what she really wanted.
でも　実際にそうだったんだよ
これは　あの子が
She told me about this dream of hers
when she was a child much shorter than me.
私よりも　ずっと背の小さな
小娘だった頃に語った夢物語だ
Honestly, I thought that era
wouldn't arrive for many more years.
正直　私は
そんな時代はずっと先のことで
あの子には実現不可能なことだと
思っていた
I didn't think she could accomplish it.
あの子は　私にとっては
To me, her life was so short
as to be practically nothing,
無にも等しいような短い人生で
人類の魔法の開祖にまで
上り詰めた
and yet she became the founder
of humanity's magic.
師匠は　いつも
判断がとても早かった
My master was always quick to decide.
まるで何かに
急かされているみたいに
It felt like she was in a hurry.
人間には寿命がある
Humans have limited lifespans.
私たちよりも
死に近い場所にいるんだ
They exist much closer to death than we do.
人生には　重大な決断を
しなければならない時が
We must all make important decisions
at several points in our lives,
いくつもあるが　あの子たちは
それを先送りにはできないんだ
but humans cannot afford to delay them.
私たちは　それを
１００年後にやっても
We can afford to wait a century or two.
２００年後にやってもいい
千年　ほったらかしに
したところで何の支障もない
Even ignoring them for a millennium
poses no obstacle,
as our time is closer to an eternity.
私たちの時間は
永遠に近いのだから
フリーレン
Frieren, many years have passed
since humanity created
人間がおよそ文明と呼べる
ものを築き上げてから
長い年月がたった
what could be called a civilization.
これから先は
時代が加速するぞ
From now on, their progress
will begin to accelerate.
A mere thousand years.
たった千年だ
たった千年で
人間の時代がやってくる
In a mere thousand years,
the era of humans will arrive.
エルフは人間に追い抜かれる
The humans will overtake us.
鍛錬を怠るなよ　フリーレン
Do not neglect your training, Frieren.
ん！
衝撃音
お前を殺す者がいるとすれば
If anyone kills you,
it will be either the Demon King…
それは魔王か
人間の魔法使いだ
or a human mage.
楽しみだね　ゼーリエ
I'm looking forward to it, Serie.
これから先
たくさんの魔法使いと
We're going to see so many
different kinds of mages and spells.
いろいろな魔法が
見られるんだね
And I'm alright (I'll be alright)
Yeah, I hear you (I care about you)
The wind teases this hair that's longer now
There's meaning in everything
Even the days that came to a halt
Now that I finally understand,
I've caught up to you
See, things that couldn't have been
Seen if it weren't for these eyes
Why? They begin to overflow
I won't ask to see you, so at least
Let me remember the past, just for today
So, if we were to meet again
No more hesitations, I'd choose the present
Anytime, anywhere, yah (wherever you are)
Anytime, anywhere (smile for me)
I'll be there (close your eyes,
and I'll always be there)
Even if there are no absolutes
I'm always aware of your thoughts
Those tears will be alright,
dawn will surely break
I'm whispering our lullaby
for you to come back home
Now, let's end this.
Worst case, we could both die.
Incredible, Ms. Frieren.
It's up to you.
This opening won't do.
We expected this much.
I'll have to do it after all.
Episode 26
The Height of Magic
So this is the height of magic.